TAHIR SYED Page | 1

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

Summary:

Software Quality Assurance professional with several years of progressive experience in testing, managing, and leading the quality assurance project to deliver quality products. Proven experience in leading SQA teams with hands on knowledge of conducting quality assurance tests for all phases of testing, including writing/implementation of test plans, test case development/execution, and logging/triaging of defects.

Core Competencies:

- Hands-on working experience in all phases of Software Quality Assurance to support web and client/server products on mobile (Android/iOS) and Windows platforms.
- Exceptional skills in in writing and developing all sort of test documentation including Test Cases, User Stories, Test Scenarios, Test Strategies, Test Plans, and Requirement Specifications.
- Knowledge of designing different test environments for manual and automated testing and executing test strategy for all kind of testing including Unit, Integration, Functional, System, Cross Browser, GUI, UAT, Regression and device testing.
- Working experience of testing on real and virtual environments for Mobile Android/iOS and Windows platforms.
- Strong knowledge of SDLC methodology and its phases with experience in both Agile and Waterfall environments.
- Knowledge of Automation tools including Selenium WebDriver, Appium, Katalon Studio and ability to manage/run scripts using these tools.
- Excellent problem solving, troubleshooting and defect finding ability by using judgmental skills.
- Good experience of back-end testing using SQL Database through writing SQL DML queries and verifying backend databases.
- Working experience with API testing using Postman and other tools.
- Working knowledge of Linux environment and Mac OS.
- Strong skills in dealing with stakeholders at all levels of project and working with different product teams.
- Demonstrated managerial and lead experience for building QA teams through mentoring, motivating and performance evaluation of team members.

Technical knowledge and skills:

Software Testing Tools:	Quality Center, Jira, Virtual Box, VMware, Fiddler, Jenkins, Zephyr, Test Rail
Operating Systems:	Windows XP, 7, 8, 10, UNIX, Mac OS, Android, iOS, Linux
Web Technologies:	XML, HTML, CSS, Java, Apache, GitHub, JMeter, Postman
Mobile OS Technologies:	Android/iOS, Android Studio, Device Anywhere, Perfecto Mobile, XCode
Database Technologies:	RDBMS, SQL Server, Microsoft Access, pgAdmin
Testing Documentation:	Test Cases, Test Plan, BRD, SOP, Design Documents
Scripting/Automation Tools:	Katalon Studio, Selenium WebDriver, Appium, JUnit, TestNG
Software Packages:	MS Office 365, MS Publisher, MS Project

Professional Experiences:

Position Title	Duration	Company	Place
Quality Assurance Test Engineer III	January 2020 – Present	Serco Inc	Herndon VA
QA Manager/Lead	March 2014 – June 2019	ComScore Inc	Reston VA
Software Quality Assurance Engineer	July 2009 – Feb 2014	ComScore Inc	Reston VA
Senior Quality Assurance Analyst	August 2008 – July 2009	Aegis Mobile	Columbia MD
Technical Integration Manager	Mar 2007 – July 2008	Amazon.com	Seattle WA
Software Test Engineer	March 2006 – Feb 2007	Motorola Inc	Seattle, WA

TAHIR SYED Page | 2

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

Professional Experience Details:

Quality Assurance Test Engineer III Serco Inc, Herndon VA Jan 2020 – Present

Work Environment: Healthcare Applications, Web UI and Database testing, API testing, Postman, Selenium, Microsoft SQL Server management Studio, VMware, Jira, TestRail

Job Responsibilities: & Achievements:

- Lead test effort for new features and monthly releases while involved in testing of web application for CMS health care services.
- Develop Test Plan, Test Scenarios, Test Cases and Test Data based on business requirements and perform
 Gap Analysis on requirements and updating test cases, test suits and test runs in TestRail.
- Write, Validate and execute SQL scripts to validate test scenarios and test results.
- Perform integration, functional, and regression testing while creating 200+ regression tests in TestRail
- · Identify, analyze and report issues for follow-up using JIRA
- Perform both front-end UI testing and back-end API testing by using Postman to create script for web API testing.
- Create training material to train and mentor new hire QA team member on products and QA processes.

QA Manager/Lead/Engineer	ComScore Inc, Reston VA	Aug 2009 – June 2019
~ · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·		

Work Environment: Web and Mobile applications testing, Data collection and validation, API testing, Selenium, Microsoft SQL, VMware, Katalon Studio, Jira, Wireshark, Fiddler, Charles, Android apps and Studio, iOS apps and Xcode, DeviceAnyWhere, Perfecto.

Job Responsibilities: & Achievements

- Lead multiple projects for end-to-end testing in Agile and Waterfall environments by working with product owners, development and test teams. Worked directly with business owners to perform user acceptance testing and assist in the production deployment activities.
- Successfully led test design and execution efforts by participating in Planning, Requirement gathering, Grooming, Scrum and Jira triage meetings. Added Jira Kanban board to Agile sprints to monitor continuous improvement and progress of project.
- Selection and setup of automation tools and created environment for Selenium WebDriver, Katalon Studio to transition regression and smoke test plans from manual to automation.
- Setup Jenkins jobs, created and assigned test cycles, review test results, created test metrics, oversee deployment of application to production, and resolve any post deployment production issues.
- Successfully managed QA team members to guide on product features, selection\training of new test tools, adding new test plans/test cases and automation of regression test plan.
- Participated in QA Audits by creating test reports using Jira and provided to third party QA process audits during Media Rating Council and Grant Thornton audits.
- Worked on Web and Mobile application testing and successfully added new test plans and test cases for multiple products to the system and implemented Automation scripts for web-based applications using TCB and Selenium.
- Performed hands-on application testing for new features on real and virtual devices by using different test tools like VMware, Virtual Box, Fiddler, Wireshark, DeviceAnyWhere and Android Studio, XCode.
- Created Jira ticket for bugs found during testing and worked on defect resolution with developers to resolve issues by providing test logs and test environment details.

TAHIR SYED Page | 3

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

Senior Quality Assurance Analyst

Aegis Mobile, Columbia MD

August 2008 – July 2009

Job Environment: Mobile Content Validation, PMP, PACT, Verizon Wireless Campaign Administrator. MMA/CTIA, Crystal Reports, N-experience platform, XML, Java, Test Director

Job Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked on mobile content validation and testing to analyze and implement Mobile Marketing Association (MMA) rules. This includes monitoring the Verizon Wireless Short Codes Services for validation and verifications of premier contents.
- Successfully implemented automation on the project by designing phone templates in XML and run the script on actual devices using Perfecto Mobile platform.

Technical Integration Manager

Amazon.com Seattle WA

Mar 2007 - July 2008

Job Environment: Kindle, RSS, XML, ATOM, E-publications, Win XP, Access, SQL Server, JIRA Bug tracking and management tool, Microsoft Share Points, MS Project.

Job Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked on integration of periodicals and newspapers for Amazon device Kindle by working with development and test teams to integrate third party contents received in XML, RSS Feeds, and atom format from local and international publishers.
- Successfully managed the project by delivering daily, weekly newspapers and magazine contents in electronic form to Kindle devices.

Software Test Engineer

Motorola INC. Seattle, WA

March 2006 - Feb 2007

Job Environment: Functional Testing, ISO 9000, Java, XML, Rational DDTS, Test Central, TOAD, UNIX, Web logic, Apache Tomcat, RSS Feeds, WAP Deck.

Job Responsibilities Achievements:

- Worked on Screen3 project for Motorola to test the contents & delivery of Screen3 application on Motorola devices and recommended several enhancements to the process.
- Successfully executed several test cycles by implementing new test plan and adding 300+ test cases to regression suite.

Education:

MS Management Information Systems Strayer University, Alexandria VA 2003-2005